americorpse.net 2004-12-07

# Corporation for National and Community Service : Privacy Policy

### About Us : Corporation Policies : Privacy Policy

**Disclaimer**  
Some of the documents on this server may contain live references (or pointers) to information created and maintained by other organizations. Please note that the Corporation does not control and cannot guarantee the relevance, timeliness, or accuracy of these outside materials. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that website. 

Except for the AmeriCorps recruitment profiles and application, the Record of Service, this website and the information it contains are considered public information, are provided as a public service by the Corporation for National and Community Service (Corporation), and may be distributed or copied. This system is monitored to ensure proper operation, to verify the functioning of applicable security features, and for other like purposes. 

Thank you for visiting the Corporation's website. This policy explains how the Corporation will handle information we learn about you from your visit to our website. 

**Browsing or Downloading**  
If you browse through our site or download information, we automatically collect and temporarily store the following anonymous information about your visit: 1) the name of the domain from which you access the Internet; 2) the date and time you access our site; and 3) the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site. We use this information for statistical purposes and to help us make our site more useful to visitors. Unless it is specifically stated otherwise, no additional information will be collected about you. We do not disclose, give, sell or transfer any personal information we receive to any outside parties, unless required for law enforcement or statute. 

**Use of Cookies**  
Sometimes we use "session cookies," which are small amounts of information stored on your computer to secure the connection during your visit. After you turn off your computer or stop using the internet, the cookies are erased. 

**Sending Us an E-mail**  
If you decide to send us personally identifying information, such as in an e-mail, that information may be subject to disclosure. It will be handled in accordance with the Privacy Act and the Freedom of Information Act, which restrict our use of it, yet permits certain disclosures. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact us at: 

Corporation for National and Community Service  
1201 New York Ave., NW  
Washington DC 20525  
202-606-5000  

**A Record of Service**  
Your e-mail address is only used because it is the best way for you to sign in with a unique identity that's easy to remember. No e-mail will be sent to you unless you ask for it. We do not share e-mail addresses with third-parties, other than to manage our database.

**Privacy Act Statement:** In compliance with the Privacy Act of 1974, the following information is provided. The collection of this information is authorized by the National and Community Service Act, as amended by the National and Community Service Trust Act of 1993. The primary purpose of the user account is to provide a means that allows individuals to record, track, and provide comment on their volunteer services. Users may also elect to be provided with additional information about other service opportunities. Providing this information is voluntary. All information contained in each user account is available only to the Corporation, on behalf of USA Freedom Corps, and will not be provided to any organization outside the Corporation. 

**Public Burden Statement:** Public reporting burden for this collection of information is estimated at 3 minutes, which includes the initial log-on, providing initial profile user, recording of volunteer service information, and log-off from the diary. Comments on the burden or content of the instrument may be sent to the Corporation for National and Community Service, Attn: Director, Public Affairs and Liaison Office, 1201 New York Avenue, N.W., Washington, D.C., 20525\. (5 C.F.R. 1320.5(b)(2)(b)) The Corporation informs the potential persons who wish to respond to the collection of information that such persons are not required to respond to the collection of information unless it displays a currently valid OMB control number which is located on this website. 

OMB Control Number - 3045-0077 Expiration Date: October 31, 2005 

**Applying to AmeriCorps**  
OMB# 3045-0054 expires 10/2005

**Public Burden Statement:** Public reporting burden for this collection of information is estimated to average 45 minutes per submission, including reviewing instructions, gathering and maintaining the data needed, and completing the form. Comments on the burden or content of this instrument may be sent to the Corporation for National Service, AmeriCorps Recruitment, 8th Floor, Attn: Noel McCaman, 1201 New York Avenue, NW, Washington, D.C. 20525. The Corporation informs people who may respond to this collection of information that they are not required to respond to the collection of information unless the OMB control number and expiration date displayed on page 1 are current and valid. (See 5 C.F.R. 1320.5(b)(2)(i).)

**PRIVACY ACT NOTICE:** The Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C § 552a) requires that the following notice be provided to you: The authority for collecting information from you in this application is contained in 42 U.S.C 12592 and 12615 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 as amended, and 42 U.S.C. 4953 of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 as amended. You are advised that submission of the information is entirely voluntary, but the requested information is required in order for you to participate in AmeriCorps programs. The principal purpose for requesting this personal information is to process your application for acceptance into an AmeriCorps program, and for other general routine purposes associated with your participation in an AmeriCorps program. These routine purposes may include disclosure of the information to federal, state, or local agencies pursuant to lawfully authorized requests, to present and former employers, references provided by you in your application, and educational institutions, for the purpose of verifying the information provided by you in your application. In some programs, the information may also be provided to federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies to determine the existence of any prior criminal convictions. The information will not otherwise be disclosed to entities outside of AmeriCorps and the Corporation for National Service without your prior written permission. 

**AmeriCorps eCommunity**  
OMB# 3045-0048 expires 3/31/2004

**Public Burden Statement:** The Agency informs the potential person who is to respond to the collection of information that such person is not required to respond to the collection of information unless it displays a currently valid OMB Control Number. Any Comments regarding this collection of information send to: (See 5 C.F.R. 1320.5(b)(2)(i).) 

**PRIVACY ACT NOTICE:** The Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C § 552a) requires that the following notice be provided to you: The collection of the information is authorized by provisions of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act, 1973 (42 U.S.C. 4950, et seq). The purpose of the card is to enhance communication between the Corporation for National and Community Service (Hereinafter "CNCS") and former members to provide them with information on CNCS activities and to seek their assistance in volunteer recruitment activities. The information must also be used for general routine uses described in 65 FR 46890, providing the information is voluntary. It will not be disclosed outside he government without written permission.

**Presidential Freedom Scholarships**  
The student's name may be used for news or publicity purposes connected with the Presidential Freedom Scholarships program. However, other student information will not be shared with anyone outside of the Corporation for National and Community Service or its designees but for the sole purpose of disbursing the scholarship. Addresses, phone numbers, student's social security number, and other personal information will not be provided to any third party.

We do not collect information for commercial marketing.

The school information and matching funds source information will not be shared with anyone outside of the Corporation for National and Community Service or its designees.

We will use information on the certification form only to process it and to respond to you directly for clarification if needed. We may also use the information for follow-up mailings related to the Presidential Freedom Scholarships program to schools, colleges, matching scholarships providers, and service sites.
